[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397db", "question": "Which US actor with a stage name of Edward was born in Romania as Emmanuel Goldenburg?", "answer": "Edward G. Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a60b", "question": "To which South American country to the Galapagos Islands belong?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d1", "question": "What distance did the Romans once define as a thousand paces?", "answer": "A mile", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa60", "question": "What two countries share Lake Geneva?", "answer": "France and Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601219f963c99d48cd169afe", "question": "What is the tallest dog breed in the world?", "answer": "Irish Wolfhound -- A Great Dane named Zeus holds the record as tallest dog ever.  As a breed, the Irish Wolfhound is the tallest.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c9", "question": "The TV show \"Frasier\" is based in what US city?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe766c3eec85e375820b289", "question": "What capital city is the only one located on the equator?", "answer": "Quito, Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbb", "question": "What novelist of westerns went by his middle name, since his first was Pearl?", "answer": "Zane Grey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcea", "question": "What two things need to be combined to form an \"interrobang\"?", "answer": "A question mark and an exclamation point", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab68", "question": "In what Australian state would you find the major port town Fremantle?", "answer": "Western Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b718", "question": "Citizens of what empire are credited with starting the tradition of gift giving?", "answer": "Romans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab189bbaab681b0929218c", "question": "What country is home to Volvo?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26d", "question": "McLean Stevenson played which character in the TV series \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Lt. Colonel Henry Blake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d4", "question": "Who was the first person to prove that planets move in elliptical orbits?", "answer": "Johannes Kepler", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc2", "question": "Who is the Greek god of love?", "answer": "Eros", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ad", "question": "Stockholm is located along what sea?", "answer": "The Baltic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc2", "question": "By tradition, what can you call yourself if you were born within the sound of London's Bow bells ringing?", "answer": "Cockney", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339579", "question": "In A Christmas Carol what song is sung outside of Scrooge's office?", "answer": "God Rest Ye Merry Gentlemen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b488", "question": "What year marked the end of production of the first generation Volkswagen Golf?", "answer": "1983", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac3", "question": "On the TV show \"Cheers\", what was Sam's nickname when he pitched for the Boston Red Sox?", "answer": "May Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb51", "question": "Founded in 1911, what company was first known as the Computing Tabulating  Recording Corporation?", "answer": "IBM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998d", "question": "What was the name of the blonde girl in the cartoon show \"Scooby-Doo\"?", "answer": "Daphne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d03", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Barney Fife?", "answer": "Sheriff Andy Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf5", "question": "What river is the setting for the novel \"The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn\"?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd4", "question": "What Robert Louis Stevenson novel was originally published under the title \"The Sea-Cook\"?", "answer": "Treasure Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58bb33a5e368446ca7bd6847", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84f", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the bronchi?", "answer": "The lungs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81c", "question": "What color blazer is presented to the Masters golf winner?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff66e6952a821ff76ae8b1b", "question": "What did people often say for photos before \"cheese\"?", "answer": "When Richard Beard, Britain's first portrait photographer, began taking family portraits, he told his clients to say \"prunes\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5eb", "question": "In which country is Angel Falls located?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a513", "question": "In which sea is the island country of Malta?", "answer": "Mediterranean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bc", "question": "What is measured in Ergs?", "answer": "Work", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b57197867df192a942e3363", "question": "Who directed the 1946 film \"It's a Wonderful Life\"?", "answer": "Frank Capra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f5", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Superfly\"?", "answer": "Curtis Mayfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b234", "question": "What athlete was born in West Baden, Indiana, in December 1956?", "answer": "Larry Bird", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339405", "question": "Who narrated the 2007 movie \"Enchanted\"?", "answer": "Julie Andrews", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eae", "question": "Who won Pulitzers for his plays \"A Delicate Balance\", \"Seascape\", and \"Three Tall Women\"?", "answer": "Edward Albee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015f975fe83fe1f2a824c33", "question": "What does the final day of Passover celebrate?", "answer": "The arrival of the Israelites to the Red Sea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa6", "question": "What is the easternmost state in the contiguous US?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b3236a0bf195a31e15d73bd", "question": "What geologic period is also known as the \"Age of Fish\"?", "answer": "Devonian period", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e7", "question": "Which African nation gained its independence on July 9, 2011?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f6", "question": "What cut of steak got its name from the New York City coach stop where it was first served?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa5843c73aa70ea0b70b3a", "question": "Which U.S. state has \"Salus Populi Suprema Lex Esto\" as its state motto?", "answer": "Missouri (The phrase translates to \"Let the welfare of the people be the supreme law\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c176", "question": "What type of instrument is a Celesta?", "answer": "Keyboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e988bebfabb9c85d8a96c", "question": "Which leader was renowned for his \"Blood and Iron\" speech?", "answer": "Otto von Bismarck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adaa", "question": "The \"Indus Valley Civilization\" is also known by what other name?", "answer": "Harappan Civilization", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c5", "question": "What island is Tokyo located on?", "answer": "Honshu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fc", "question": "What part of a sailor's uniform can be used in an emergency as a flotation device?", "answer": "The pants (also the hat)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded1beea2747c8aff16d36", "question": "What year gave birth to the word \"motel\"?", "answer": "1925", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffcd51cf6db9ac4808d04", "question": "Which flag becomes the flag of Poland when turned upside down?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c7", "question": "Which actor of the Silent Era was known as\"'The Man Of A Thousand Faces\"?", "answer": "Lon Chaney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0fe", "question": "In what country was Adolf Hitler born?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66c16a5bfecdd737e088e", "question": "The name for PEZ candy came from the German word for what?", "answer": "Peppermint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a1", "question": "What traditionally tops the meat in a shepherd's pie?", "answer": "Mashed potatoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ffb", "question": "In what movie is $200,000 of Confederate gold buried in the grave marked \"Unknown\" next to Arch Stanton?", "answer": "The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3dc", "question": "Which famous piece of artwork depicts the \"Battle of Hastings\"?", "answer": "Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6017380944491cbd7c5a1793", "question": "During World War II, prisoners wearing an uninverted red triangle in a concentration camp signified the prisoners were what?", "answer": "An enemy\u00a0POW, a spy or traitor, a military\u00a0deserter\u00a0or a military criminal.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e86006d333868d34d747", "question": "Who was the top Australian flying ace in World War I?", "answer": "Robert Little", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bb356622627b8fe95581bde", "question": "What year was the Jeddah Flagpole constructed in Saudi Arabia, becoming the tallest flagpole in the world?", "answer": "2014", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c35b", "question": "How many feet do snails have?", "answer": "One", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba16a874c93a3298b2126", "question": "What is Kenny G's real surname?", "answer": "Gorelick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b39501dd7bf43be5e7b2", "question": "A group of herring is called what?", "answer": "An army", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c46f", "question": "What does the Scoville scale measure?", "answer": "The spicy heat of chili peppers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b848", "question": "What is the lowest hand that beats a straight in poker?", "answer": "Flush", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3cefff048f679a45ab44", "question": "Which animal can cause a tularemia infection in humans while being skinned for cooking purposes?", "answer": "Rabbits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdd61900499cffc60b8423a", "question": "Which ancient people first mined and smelted copper?", "answer": "Egyptians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f0a", "question": "What actor, despite playing a small role, received top billing in 1978's \"Superman\" movie?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc274ec223966ae8f8876", "question": "Which Disney princess had two stepsisters, Anastasia and Drizella?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea43beff048f679a45ab87", "question": "What enzyme is responsible for breaking down starches?", "answer": "Amylase", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c425", "question": "What name is usually given to bananas cultivated for cooking?", "answer": "Plantains", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59524530736d4be723796b6c", "question": "What French impressionist painter died in 1926", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e9", "question": "Which herb is used to make \"Pesto Sauce\"", "answer": "Basil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc1", "question": "What band's Greatest Hits album set a US record by going 29 times platinum?", "answer": "Eagles'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b17e", "question": "In what year did Pierre Trudeau become the 15th Prime Minister of Canada?", "answer": "1968", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab97", "question": "Which sea separates Greece from Asia Minor?", "answer": "Aegean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8ff1101dd7bf43be5e860", "question": "Whose birthday is celebrated on the third Monday in February in the US?", "answer": "President George Washington's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c36dd815febcc896f926b", "question": "Calypso, cattleya and laelia are types of which flowering plant?", "answer": "Orchid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71b", "question": "What word describes a horse with a golden coat and a white or silver mane and tail?", "answer": "Palomino", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a5", "question": "What NFLer was nickname the \"Minister of Defense\"?", "answer": "Reggie White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c379", "question": "What name is given to male rhinoceroses?", "answer": "Bulls", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c40e", "question": "A Roman nose is notable for its prominent what?", "answer": "Bridge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40d", "question": "Devil's Island, once the world's most notorious penal colony, is located off the coast of what country?", "answer": "French Guiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067ce8ff9c0647b50a8071", "question": "What is the name of the sixth expansion to the World of Warcraft game universe?", "answer": "World of Warcraft: Legion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5a", "question": "What president delivered his \"Fourteen Points\" speech in Congress in 1918?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a834", "question": "Which two countries does The Netherlands border?", "answer": "Belgium and Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5989a972cb8751d53e7d7600", "question": "The State of Washington was originally going to be called what?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f9", "question": "Coffee heiress Abigail Folger was one of the victims of which criminal?", "answer": "Charles Manson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfc779dc5ec6cd98a831d", "question": "What Brazilian artist was known for his fireballs?", "answer": "In the 1960s, H\u00e9lio Oiticica produced a series of small box-shaped interactive sculptures called B\u00f3lides (fireballs).", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a835", "question": "What US state is the source of the Arkansas, Platte, and Rio Grande rivers?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f4", "question": "What day is the Super Bowl always played on?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c7", "question": "What planet was Mork from in the TV show \"Mork & Mindy\"?", "answer": "Ork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ffa863a3a814d89068c5c", "question": "Winkle is a species of edible what?", "answer": "Sea snails", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fedd8a96ce05a3942286d72", "question": "What is the name of the highly-entertaining main villain of \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Agent Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3c", "question": "What \"Animal House\" actor made his show-biz debut as the voice of TV's Jonny Quest?", "answer": "Tim Matheson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace4", "question": "How many stones make up each of Stonehenge's trilithons?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8d", "question": "Dakar is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd4da7e83c707845b2161", "question": "How many different shapes of four-connected blocks are there in \"Tetris\"?", "answer": "7", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2be", "question": "The first atomic bomb test split an atom of what fissionable element?", "answer": "Plutonium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca53", "question": "The rate of change of velocity is known as what?", "answer": "Acceleration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feccf22ec223966ae8f88b2", "question": "What does police chief Martin Brody use to kill the shark at the end of \"Jaws\"?", "answer": "A scuba tank", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a552183e1c6f9840ba3192", "question": "In Greek mythology, what were Medusa, Stheno and Euryale collectively known as?", "answer": "The Gorgons", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c473", "question": "What is the name of Mars' smaller moon?", "answer": "Deimos", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abaf", "question": "Annapolis is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37f", "question": "A male duck is properly known as what?", "answer": "A drake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc9b", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Oche\"?", "answer": "Darts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc1bb6de0eb824d4052e2", "question": "What Islands make up the U.S. Virgin Islands?", "answer": "The U.S. Virgin Islands consist of Saint Croix, Saint Thomas, Saint John, and Water Island, alongside 50 other tiny islets.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3b", "question": "What did \"abolitionists\" oppose?", "answer": "Slavery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a69e", "question": "What two lakes meet at the Straits of Mackinac?", "answer": "Lake Michigan and Lake Huron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51717ff04d658268c92f8", "question": "What was Cleopatra's ethnicity?", "answer": "Despite being born in Egypt, Cleopatra's ancestral roots are planted in Macedonian Greece.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b261", "question": "What legendary chief's death in December 1890, led directly to the famous massacre at Wounded Knee?", "answer": "Sitting Bull's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfbb", "question": "March, April and May are the only months that have what?", "answer": "Anagrams - Charm, Ripal, Yam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d1", "question": "Angel Falls, the highest waterfall in the world, is located in what country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60172cff44491cbd7c5a177e", "question": "Who commanded the American troops during World War I?", "answer": "General John J. Pershing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f556ff048f679a45aad5", "question": "Pathophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Disease", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1c", "question": "General John J. Pershing was in command of the American troops during what war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ab", "question": "Kansas City is built at the confluence of what two rivers?", "answer": "Kansas River and Missouri River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b3c501dd7bf43be5e7b4", "question": "What TV show inspired the term \"spam\" for junk email?", "answer": "\"Monty Python's Flying Circus\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3a29c73aa70ea0b70ade", "question": "What river runs through Baghdad?", "answer": "The\u00a0Tigris River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339651", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Paulie\"?", "answer": "Parrot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc4456ce05a3942286f2f", "question": "Robert De Niro and Al Pacino acted together for the first time in which film?", "answer": "Heat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c45f877e98cb9777899e", "question": "Which country was known as South West Africa until 1990?", "answer": "Namibia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49a", "question": "What was Belize called until 1973?", "answer": "British Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e24", "question": "What kind of dinosaur is the Flintstones' Dino?", "answer": "A snorkasaurus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbdf", "question": "What is the last name of the founder of the Papa John's pizza chain?", "answer": "Schnatter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a3c839a039f3d7859290ffa", "question": "In the TV Show \"Gunsmoke\", who portrayed the blacksmith, Quint Asper?", "answer": "Burt Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5de655d2f89b9ec3da2d335b", "question": "What belt driven engine accessory pressurizes the intake air in an automobile engine?", "answer": "Supercharger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beab", "question": "Who got his signature left-ear piercing in 1986, after interviewee Liza Minnelli encouraged him to do it?", "answer": "Ed Bradley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339426", "question": "What is Sweeny Todd's real name in the 2007 movie by the same name?", "answer": "Benjamin Barker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66dc0a5bfecdd737e08a6", "question": "How many candles are lit throughout the eight nights of Hanukkah?", "answer": "44", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a4", "question": "How old was astronaut Neil Armstrong when he passed away in 2012?", "answer": "82", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab19", "question": "What country is the Arch of Hardian located in?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a1a3f312f2a7826b9b872b", "question": "What do the letters in UNESCO's name stand for?", "answer": "United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912a", "question": "What year was Camille Saint-Saens' opera \"Samson and Delilah\" first performed?", "answer": "1877", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339551", "question": "How did Rerun get his nickname on \"What's Happening\"?", "answer": "Repeating classes he failed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e7", "question": "In the movie \"Three men and a Baby\" what was Michael's occupation?", "answer": "Cartoonist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a3", "question": "What agricultural crop is Cuba's main export?", "answer": "Sugar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72d", "question": "What is Santa's name in France?", "answer": "Pere Noel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11c", "question": "What year did the US first host the Summer Olympic Games?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff14323b0ee8c595b6d39b1", "question": "Which artist painted \"The Gleaners\"?", "answer": "Jean Francois Millet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c018", "question": "What is the Italian name for squid in a restaurant?\u00a0", "answer": "Calamari\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7bf34877e98cb97778966", "question": "Lake Titicaca sits on the border between what two nations?", "answer": "Bolivia and Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e19afe83fe1f2a824b97", "question": "Why did the British Royal Navy attack French warships at Mers-el-Kebir?", "answer": "The French crews refused to surrender their ships when the British requested", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd770e347d002c297e4c3", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Diana?", "answer": "Artemis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a791", "question": "What strait connects the Persian Gulf to the Gulf of Oman?", "answer": "Strait of Hormuz", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60078566bd51d85e222ab65e", "question": "Who said: \"I\u2019m the president of the United States, and I\u2019m not going to eat any more broccoli\"?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush (He once made a joke that the workers in the Office of Personnel Management would get merit pay \"in broccoli\").", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f8c601dd7bf43be5e848", "question": "Who said, \"I don't make jokes. I just watch the government and report the facts\"?", "answer": "Will Rogers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b8e", "question": "What form of writing is literally translated to \"sacred writings\"?", "answer": "Hieroglyphics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a86", "question": "What poet coined the phrase \"candy is dandy, but liquor is quicker\"?", "answer": "Ogden Nash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec26ac8dc25ca9e12ef64e", "question": "What is a male goose called?", "answer": "Gander", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff516cfff04d658268c92f5", "question": "Who came up with \"The Allegory of the Cave\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30d", "question": "What flowers are known as \"mums\"?", "answer": "Chrysanthemums", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2d", "question": "Who wrote \"Our Lady of the Flowers\" while in prison?", "answer": "Jean Genet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f2", "question": "Who is typically referred to as \"The Father of History\"?", "answer": "Herodotus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339068", "question": "What is the name of the dog from the story \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Max", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5e296ce05a3942286e30", "question": "Which horror movie\u2019s sequel has the tagline, \"They\u2019re back\"?", "answer": "\"Poltergeist\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e16506d333868d34d727", "question": "Who wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\"?", "answer": "Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b308", "question": "Who received a speeding ticket while driving his Porsche Spyder on September 30, 1955?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b36601dd7bf43be5e7ae", "question": "A group of wild cats are called what?", "answer": "A destruction", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caab", "question": "The cecum is part of which intestine?", "answer": "Large intestine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc12", "question": "What designer was the first man to appear on the cover of British Vogue?", "answer": "Manolo Blahnik", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a629", "question": "What U.S. state capital city is located at the southern shores of Lake Oahe?", "answer": "Pierre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339474", "question": "In what city does the movie \"Mrs. Doubtfire\" take place?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339545", "question": "What popular character was formally addressed as Don Diego de la Vega?", "answer": "Zorro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b878", "question": "What color does the bride commonly wear in China?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339289", "question": "In the movie \"The Hunger Games\", who fights with a bow and arrow besides Katness?", "answer": "Glimmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958a", "question": "What male actor plays the lead role in the 2005 movie \"The Island\"?", "answer": "Ewen McGregor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f706b4e2c7fbd3896745", "question": "What is Kahlua flavored with?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21e", "question": "Who was Randy Mario Poffo better known as?", "answer": "\"Macho Man\" Randy Savage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63a", "question": "Which bird lays the largest eggs?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ec", "question": "What is added to cognac and absinthe to make a Sazerac cocktail?", "answer": "Sugar cube and Peychaud's bitters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a000", "question": "What British TV series featured Eddie \"Fitz\" Fitzgerald and Jane \"Panhandle\" Penhaligon?", "answer": "Cracker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ccf7c47b37b32637bdc44c8", "question": "What is the smallest country by area and population?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16878f7c52aae91cc07c7", "question": "\"Cardice\" is another term for what?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57c", "question": "What US city is nicknamed the \"Birthplace of the Nation\"?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133899c", "question": "The John Knowles novel \"A Separate Peace\" is narrated by which character?", "answer": "Gene", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600243894be4723ccac22198", "question": "What was the name of the first book in Laura Ingalls Wilder\u2019s \"Little House\" series?", "answer": "\"Little House in the Big Woods\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c708877e98cb977789c7", "question": "In which state is the Edmund Pettus Bridge located?", "answer": "Alabama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc34cec223966ae8f887d", "question": "Tiger Woods set or tied 27 records at which 1997 PGA tournament?", "answer": "The Masters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f8", "question": "How long is a round in boxing?", "answer": "3 minutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173fdc44491cbd7c5a17b7", "question": "John the Baptist's father was who?", "answer": "The father of John the Baptist was Zechariah.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c964", "question": "Osteoporosis primarily affects what?", "answer": "Bones", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67f", "question": "Who was the first American president to appear on the cover of \"People\" magazine?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce4", "question": "What fashion brand was co-founded by artist Justin Timberlake?", "answer": "William Rast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5971e0fd89261e916c8e09b0", "question": "Which European city is the game \"Assassin's Creed Unity\" set in?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a159", "question": "Which group starred in \"Magical Mystery Tour\"?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eae31f83302ff91e46486", "question": "What animal was the Egyptian God Horus depicted as?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa2", "question": "A story of ones own life is referred to as what?", "answer": "Autobiography", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600b86681d8c1817608d53e4", "question": "What does the \"E\" stand for in Chuck E. Cheese?", "answer": "Entertainment (Restaurant founder, Nolan Bushnell, happens to be the founder of Atari.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca56", "question": "What do insects do through their spiracles?", "answer": "Breathe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5f", "question": "What 1965 novel by Leo Herlihy recounts the story of Joe Buck and Rico \u201cRatso\u201d Rizzo?", "answer": "Midnight Cowboy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600241204be4723ccac22170", "question": "What Italian sculptor/architect is credited with creating the Baroque style?", "answer": "Gian Lorenzo Bernini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358ab15db0d66a186cb554", "question": "From which state does the US band \"The Great Divide\" originate?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f164acef9b80650dbe7f92c", "question": "How many British Admiral-class battlecruisers were cancelled in 1919?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f839fe83fe1f2a824c2a", "question": "The \"St. Valentine's Day Massacre\" was perpetrated by which historical figure?", "answer": "Al Capone ordered the murders on February 14, 1929, but the primary target got away.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989aa42cb8751d53e7d7603", "question": "Who served as the United States Ambassador to Japan from 2013-2017?", "answer": "Caroline Bouvier Kennedy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c37bc815febcc896f9273", "question": "What is the tenth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Capricorn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a0", "question": "Which planet in our solar system is named after the Roman God of the sea?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ca", "question": "Which Shakespeare play tells a love story between a Capulet and a Montague?", "answer": "Romeo and Juliet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049aedcf93664eb104869c", "question": "Marvel Comics was acquired by which major media and entertainment company in 2009?", "answer": "The Walt Disney Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb668f5dad637d903c8838", "question": "The Maluku islands (informally known as the Spice Islands) belong to which country?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f980fa5fdd6dd25324f8", "question": "Who would use a mashie niblick?", "answer": "A golfer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c92", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Orbit City?", "answer": "The Jetsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339abe", "question": "What was Drew Barrymore's character\u2019s name in \"E.T.: The Extra-Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Gertie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca18", "question": "What is a theodolite used for?", "answer": "Surveys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff7c11b2b316f4693fb679b", "question": "What is the space between windows called?", "answer": "Interfenestration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a817", "question": "What city is the fashion center of Italy?", "answer": "Milan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab95b386faa38a764be518", "question": "Before starting to produce cars in the late 1940s, what did SAAB originally manufacture?", "answer": "Aircrafts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015eaf2fe83fe1f2a824bf6", "question": "Which Native American tribe took part in the first Thanksgiving feast?", "answer": "Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d4b", "question": "What popular architect design The Louvre's distinctive glass pyramid in its central courtyard?", "answer": "I.M. Pei", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d61", "question": "Who wrote the 1963 novel \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Pierre Boulle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3eb0d38e4e5d4832e6318", "question": "What name was given to the west wind by the Greeks?", "answer": "Zephyrus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5be57f6c5415ba52ed6f0aaa", "question": "What type of creature is a \"sidewinder\"?", "answer": "A snake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff516a8ff04d658268c92f2", "question": "What was America's first major fast food chain?", "answer": "White Castle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb4", "question": "How old was General Tom Thumb when he joined P. T. Barnum's circus in 1843?", "answer": "5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08d", "question": "Who hosted the 1997 Grammy Awards?", "answer": "Ellen Degeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e8", "question": "What surname for John in \"The Importance of Being Earnest\" did Oscar Wilde take from the seaside town he vacationed at?", "answer": "Worthing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339824", "question": "What do the letters B.B. stand for in B.B. King?", "answer": "Blues Boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339878", "question": "In Star Trek, what planet is Spock from?", "answer": "Vulcan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f15", "question": "What author created Lilliput?", "answer": "Jonathan Swift", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015f6e7fe83fe1f2a824c1e", "question": "After his crucifixion, who takes down the body of Jesus Christ off the cross of Calvary?", "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ab", "question": "What bone, to which your ribs are attached, gets its name from the Greek for breastbone?", "answer": "Sternum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a796", "question": "What city was Russia's capital before Moscow?", "answer": "St. Petersburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339109", "question": "What popular book did Viktor Frankl write in 1946?", "answer": "Man's Search for Meaning", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66bdba5bfecdd737e088a", "question": "What is the only bird to have its own year on the Chinese calendar?", "answer": "Rooster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef96266ce05a3942286e9b", "question": "What was Meryl Streep's birth name?", "answer": "Mary Louise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c024", "question": "What is the fear of riding in vehicles known as?", "answer": "Ochophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c8", "question": "Who built the world's first free-standing geodesic dome in 1949?", "answer": "Buckminster Fuller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e7", "question": "When did actor W. C. Fields die?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc8d36de0eb824d4052ff", "question": "Which two European countries are located along Turkey\u2019s northwestern border?", "answer": "Greece and Bulgaria -- Turkey also borders three central Asian countries, as well as, three Middle Eastern countries.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a01e", "question": "What day of the week do the Bangles wish it was in \"Manic Monday\"?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff5", "question": "Who was the first African American to host a TV show?", "answer": "Nat King Cole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7c", "question": "What nickname was given to Al Capone?", "answer": "Scarface", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b028", "question": "The major battle of what city was fought on January 8, 1815?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6990f20565ad31a57c740", "question": "What legendary athlete lit the Olympic torch at the 1996 Atlanta Olympics?", "answer": "Mohammed Ali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c481", "question": "What is a group of feral horses called?", "answer": "A band", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6002449b4be4723ccac221a6", "question": "What artist is known for having painted the Moulin Rouge?", "answer": "Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec produced a collection of provocative images of the decadent life of 19th century Paris.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5904995ecf93664eb1048690", "question": "What is the capital of Antigua and Barbuda?", "answer": "St. John's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a8", "question": "Whose California grave marker reads \"1935 - 1998 And the Beat Goes On?\"", "answer": "Sonny Bono's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c917877e98cb977789ee", "question": "Where is the centuries-old Maiden Tower?", "answer": "Baku, Azerbaijan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff50fc3d24dd593ee3eacc6", "question": "Which US state has the highest relative humidity?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1f", "question": "In golf, what is the traditional name for a number 3 wood?", "answer": "Spoon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f20", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Arnie Cunningham?", "answer": "Christine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac9a", "question": "What is the FBI motto?", "answer": "Fidelity, Bravery and Integrity", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb15", "question": "What city was home to the NBA's Jazz before moving to Utah?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee2", "question": "Which US boxer was known as \"The Manessa Mauler\"?", "answer": "Jack Dempsey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b103", "question": "What infamous gangster was betrayed by \"the lady in red\"?", "answer": "John Dillinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636f8f967692ea851899b6", "question": "In what game do you have the greatest chance of landing on Illinois Avenue?", "answer": "Monopoly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945f", "question": "How does Jack die in the movie \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "He freezes to death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfdff2db668d7dfe168b5b5", "question": "Which duo is credited with inventing the \"Spinning Frame\"?", "answer": "Richard Arkwright and John Kay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973c", "question": "Who won an Oscar for the theme song from the movie \"Shaft\"?", "answer": "Isaac Hayes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a672", "question": "The city of Albuquerque is located in what desert?", "answer": "Chihuahua Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b316", "question": "On April 11, 1990, California Angel Mike Witt combined with which starter to pitch a no-hit victory?", "answer": "Mark Langston", "category": "history"}]